Ran and I met Suzuki Sonoko at her mountain villa
ذهبتُ مع ران لمنزل سوزوكي سونوكو الجبليّ
to view the autumn leaves.
لمشاهدة أوراق الخريف
Also there was Sonoko's sister and graduate student, Ayako,
والتقينا هناك أخت سونوكو، طالبة الدراسات العليا أياكو
Ayako's old college friend and import car broker, Ota Masaru,
وصديق أياكو من أيام الدراسة وسمسار السيّارات المستوردة أوتا ماسارو
the film magazine editor, Sumiya Hiroki,
ومحرّر صحيفة الأفلام سوميا هيروكي
the food company employee, Takahashi Ryoichi,
وموظّف شركة الغذاء تاكاهاشي ريويتشي
and scriptwriter Ikeda Chikako, for a total of eight people.
وكاتبة السيناريو إيكيدا تشيكاكو، كان مجموعنا 8 أشخاص
The incidents began when a creepy man in bandages
بدأت الحوادث بمحاولة رجل مُريب ملفوف بالضماد
tried to kill Ran in the forest!
قتل ران التائهة في الغابة
That night, after the only bridge out was destroyed,
،وفي تلك الليلة، بعدما قُطع الجسر الوحيد
Ikeda Chikako was caught and killed by the bandaged man!
أخذ رجل الضماد إيكيدا تشيكاكو وقتلها
And then he tried to kill Ran again!
ثمّ حاول قتل ران مُجدداً
Why? Why is he after Ran?!
!لمَ؟ لمَ يستهدف رجل الضماد ران؟
The Mountain Lodge Bandage Man Murder Case (Part 2).
جريمة قتل رجل ضماد السكن الجبلي (الجزء الثاني)
What?!
ما-ماذا؟
She was attacked again?!
!هاجمها مُجدداً؟
By that bandaged man?!
!رجل الضماد؟
Apparently so...
يبدو ذلك
Are you all right?
أأنت بخير؟
Yeah!
أجل
But how did he get in?
لكن كيف دخل؟
You did lock the window, right?
ألم تقفلي النافذة؟
Yes...
بلى
Hey!
انظروا
What is it?
ماذا؟
The window's been cut!
قُطِع زجاج النافذة
Aha!
هكذا إذاً
He put his hand through to unlock it!
!أدخل يده وفتح القفل
But we're on the 2nd floor! How'd he get up here?
لكنّنا في الطابق الثاني، كيف صعد هنا؟
Ota! There!
!أوتا! تلك
This is one serious guy...
يا للوغد
And then he--
...ثمّ
That's odd-- it's pouring outside!
غريب، المطر يهطل بغزارة خارجاً
If he snuck in from out there,
،إن تسلّل من الخارج
it's safe to assume he would track mud inside...
فيُفترض أنّ تكون هناك آثار وحل في الداخل
But there isn't any at all!
لكن لا شيء منها أبداً
Why?!
لمَ؟
Anyway, it's dangerous to be alone.
بأيّ حال، من الخطر أن نتفرّق
Let's all wait in the dining room until morning.
لنجتمع في غرفة الطعام ونبقى للصباح
Good call...
أ-أجل
I hate piggyback rides! They're so stupid!
!أكره صعود الظهر! هذا سخيف
What are you talking about? You sprained your ankle!
!ما الذي تقوله؟ لويتَ كاحلك
Ayako-san. Isn't that the thing
...أياكو-سان، أليس هذا
Chikako-san was wearing around her neck?
ما كانت تضعه تشيكاكو-سان على عنقها؟
Yes, this is Chikako's choker.
صحيح، إنّه شريط عنقها
Right after you and the others chased after the bandaged man,
،بعدما لاحقتم جميعاً رجل الضماد
I found it lying by the front door.
وجدتُه عند الباب الأمامي
What the hell is the guy thinking?!
!ما الذي يفكّر به رجل الضماد ذاك؟
Killing Chikako and attacking Ran-chan twice!
!هاجم ران-تشان مرّتين فوق قتل تشيكاكو؟
What if he wants to kill us all?
ماذا لو كان يريد قتلنا جميعاً؟
No way...
...مستحيل
You can't be serious...
...لا يُعقل
That's strange.
غريب
He carried Chikako-san into the forest afterward,
حمل تشيكاكو-سان للغابة معه بعدها
so if her choker did fall off, it would've been there.
لذا لو سرق شريط عنقها فيُفترض أن يكون هناك
So what was it doing by the front door?
فلمَ كان عند الباب الأمامي؟
Why didn't you use your karate to beat him up when he attacked you?
لمَ لم تستعملي الكاراتيه وتبرحيه ضرباً عندما هاجمك؟
That's not like you, Ran!
!ليس من طباعك يا ران
I couldn't help it; I'm scared of monsters and stuff like that...
ليس بيدي حيلة، فأنا أخاف الأشباح والوحوش وما شابه
There's no need to worry.
لا حاجة للقلق
There's six of us, and one of him.
نحن ستّة، وهو بمفرده
I doubt he's dumb enough to attack six--
...لن يكون قادراً على هزيمة
Ota-san?
أوتا-سان؟
Ouch!
!تألمتُ أيضاً
Conan-kun!
!كونان-كن
What the hell was that for?!
!ما الذي تفعله يا صبيّ؟
There's seven people here, not six!
!نحن سبعة ولسنا ستّة
You're just a kid; you don't count!
!لا يدخل الأطفال الحساب
That's not true.
ليس صحيحاً
He protected me when I was attacked!
فقد حماني عندما تعرّضتُ للهجوم
Isn't that right?
صحيح؟
Thanks!
شكراً
Say, Ran. Did you get a look at the guy's face?
ران، هل نظرتِ لوجه رجل الضماد عن قرب؟
No...
كلا
I know his build, though!
لكنّي أعرف بُنيته
I couldn't see his face since it was wrapped in bandages,
لم أتمكن من رؤية وجهه بوضوح بما أنّه كان ملفوفاً بالضماد
but I know his figure because of when I jumped onto him...
لكنّي أعرف بُنيته لأنّي تمسّكتُ به
His chest was about this big,
كان صدره بهذا الحجم تقريباً
so he wasn't especially skinny or fat...
فلم يكن بديناً أو نحيلاً بالتحديد
Like we can believe what some kid says.
كأنّ بإمكاننا تصديق كلام طفل
Sumiya-san's video camera!
كاميرا تصوير سوميا-سان
I'm pretty sure he was recording when the bandaged man
وفقما أذكر، كان رجل الضماد يصوّر عندما
ran off with Chikako-san...
هرب ومعه تشيكاكو-سان
There he is!
!ها هو
Just as I thought, she has the choker on!
كما ظننت، إنّها ترتدي شريط العنق
Which means that her body, which the bandaged man
ما يعني أنّ جثّتها التي كان يمسكها رجل الضماد
was holding when they passed by the window,
عندما مرّ بالنافذة
somehow went through this lodge.
عبرت داخل السكن لسببٍ ما
Someone inside this lodge could have carried her
كان بإمكان أحدٍ داخل السكن حملها
through the house and out into the forest.
من البيت للغابة
But everyone was in this room when she was taken!
!لكن كان الجميع في هذه الغرفة عندما أُخذت
Shall I make us some coffee?
هل أعدّ قهوة؟
Yeah, good idea.
فكرة حسنة
Say. You were the last one to see Chikako-san, right?
أخبريني، كنتِ آخر من رأى تشيكاكو-سان، صحيح يا أياكو-سان؟
Yes...
أجل
Did she seem out of the ordinary at all?
هل بدا عليها أمرٌ غريب وقتها؟
Now that you mention it,
...بذكرك ذلك
she read a note that had been slipped beneath her door...
قرأتْ رسالةً كانت تحت باب غرفتها
She suddenly turned very pale...
شحب لون وجهها فجأةً
Ah, so she was drawn outside by that note!
!فهمت، استدرجتها الرسالة للخارج
That's why her slippers were by the back door--
لهذا السّبب كان خُفّاها عند الباب الخلفي
that's where she snuck out from...
حيث يمكنها التسلل دون أن يراها أحد
And only someone on the inside could have put the note there.
والوحيد الذي كان بمقدوره وضع الرسالة هناك هو أحد المقيمين هنا
Does that mean the killer is in this room?!
!أكان قاتلها بيننا حقاً؟
But why did he try to kill Ran twice?
لكن لمَ حاول قتل ران مرّتين؟
I don't know his motive for killing Chikako-san,
لا أعرف دافع قتله لتشيكاكو-سان
but why Ran, who came here at a moment's notice?
لكن لمَ هاجم ران التي شاركت في آخر لحظة؟
Wait a minute! What if she had--
...لحظة! ماذا لو وقتها
I'm sorry! My mistake!
!آسفة! أخطأت
Hey, Ran-neechan.
أخبريني يا ران-نيتشان
What?
ماذا؟
When we got here,
،عندما وصلنا هنا
you opened everyone's door by accident, right?
فتحتِ أبواب غرف الجميع بالخطأ، صحيح؟
Yeah...
أجل
Did you see anything?
ألم تري شيئاً وقتها؟
Like what?
ما قصدك؟
Like a cape or bandages?
مثل معطف أو ضماد؟
Don't tell me this kid suspects us?!
ما الذي يقوله هذا الطفل؟ أتشكّ بنا؟
Don't pay attention to him; he just loves playing detective!
!لا-لا تهتموا له رجاءً! إنّه يحب لعب لعبة التحرّي
You really didn't see anything?
لم تري شيئاً حقاً؟
I didn't see anything!
!بالطبع لا
They were all changing clothes so I shut the doors right away!
كانوا يغيّرون ملابسهم فأغلقت الباب فوراً
Now that I think about it,
...إن أعدتُ التفكير، هناك ما حيّر بالي
something's been bugging me ever since...
مُذ ذاك الوقت
I don't think it was important,
لا أظنّه مُهماً جدّاً
but I can't remember what it was...
لكن لا أستطيع تذكره
Try to remember, Ran-neechan!
!تذكّري يا ران-نيتشان
The power's out!
!انقطعت الكهرباء
The lightning knocked out a power line!
!أسقطت الصاعقة للتوّ برج طاقة
I'm scared!
!أشعر بالخوف
I'll get candles from the kitchen!
سأجلب أعواد شمع من المطبخ
You gonna be alright by yourself?
أستكونين بخيرٍ بمفردك؟
I'll come with you!
!سأرافقك
Me too!
!وأنا
This should help for a little while...
يُفترض أن تحلّ المشكلة لبرهة
What was that?
ما كان ذلك الصوت؟
It came from the dining room.
أتى من غرفة الطعام حيث الجميع
Could it be the bandaged man again?!
!أيمكن أنّه رجل الضماد مُجدداً؟
Are you okay, Conan-kun?!
!أأنت بخيرٍ يا كونان-كن؟
That was mean, Ran-neechan!
!كان ذلك قاسياً يا ران-نيتشان
I'm so sorry!
آسفة
That's--
...ذاك
Isn't that an axe?
لحظة، أليس فأساً؟
So that person just now was--
...الشخص الذي كان هنا إذاً
The bandaged man is after Ran!
!رجل الضماد يلاحق ران فعلاً
But why her?!
!لكن لمَ هي؟
That sounded like Sonoko!
!كان ذلك صوت سونوكو
Ran-neechan! Come on! Hurry!
!ران-نيتشان! لنسرع
The upstairs window is broken!
!النافذة العلوية مكسورة
Ran-neechan! Go up to the window!
!ران-نيتشان، اذهبي للنافذة
Ayako-san! Could you hold these?!
أياكو-سان، هلّا حملتِ هذه؟
Look at this mess!
يا للفوضى
The floor's covered in broken glass!
الأرض مليئة بكسور الزجاج
The bandaged man must've broken through this window...
لا بدّ أنّ رجل الضماد دخل من هذه النافذة
No, he didn't!
كلا
One of the locks is undone!
أحد القفلين مفتوح
If he really did break in through this window...
...لو
...then it should still be locked!
فيُفترض أن تبقى الأقفال
But it's not!
لكنّها ليست كذلك
Most likely, he unlocked it from the inside,
ما يعني أنّه فتحها من الداخل غالباً
stepped onto the veranda, closed the window,
وخرج للشرفة وأغلق النافذة
and then smashed it to make it look like he broke in from outside!
!ثمّ حطّم الزجاج ليخدعنا أنّه دخل من الخارج
He snuck in from the 2nd floor again?!
تسلّل من الطابق الثاني مُجدداً؟
Yeah, he probably jumped onto the veranda from that tree...
أجل، أتى للشرفة عبر تلك الشجرة مُجدداً على الأرجح
No doubt about it!
لا شكّ
The maniac who killed Chikako-san
المجرم المجنون الذي قتل تشيكاكو-سان
and attacked Ran three times is in this very room!
!وهاجم ران ثلاث مرّات موجودٌ بيننا
What are those grooves?
ما هذه الخطوط؟
That's it! Now I understand!
!هكذا إذاً! فهمت
That was a trick!
!كانت حيلة
Thanks, Ran-neechan!
شكراً لك يا ران-نيتشان
But why is the bandaged man intent on killing Ran?
لكن لمَ رجل الضماد مصرٌّ على قتل ران؟
What exactly did she see?
ما الذي رأته بالضبط؟
I didn't see anything!
!بالطبع لا
They were all changing clothes so I shut the doors right away!
كانوا يغيّرون ملابسهم فأغلقت الباب فوراً
What if he's actually--
...ماذا لو كان
So the bandaged man really is him!
!رجل الضماد... هو إذاً
If so, then the three mysteries--
...عندها، الألغاز الثلاثة
the reason why the bandaged man passed by the window
سبب مرور رجل الضماد بالنافذة مع تشيكاكو-سان
with Chikako-san for everyone to see,
...كي نراه جميعاً
how he was able to carry the body into the forest unnoticed,
...وحمله الجثّة للغابة دون أن يلاحظه أحد
and the reason he's after Ran--
...وسبب مهاجمته لران
they all fit!
!توضّحت الصُّورة
Alright!
!حسنٌ
Ran's the only detective I can use here!
!لا لديّ سوى ران لتؤدي دور المتحرّي
Say, where are the candles I gave you earlier?
المعذرة، أين أعواد الشمع التي أعطيتك يا أياكو-سان؟
I missed!
!أخطأت التصويب
Sonoko?
سونوكو؟
What's wrong, Sonoko?!
!ما الخطب يا سونوكو؟
Damn! I have no choice but to use Sonoko now!
!تبّاً! لا أمامي سوى استعمال سونوكو الآن
Sonoko!
!سونوكو
I just figured it out...
...لـ-لقد اكتشفت
I know who killed Chikako-san!
!هويّة المجرم الذي قتل تشيكاكو-سان
What're you talking about, Sonoko-chan?
ما الذي تقولينه يا سونوكو-تشان؟
The killer's obviously that bandaged guy!
المجرم رجل الضماد بالطبع
Yeah. He's probably in the forest right now,
صحيح، إنّه في الغابة الآن غالباً
just waiting to get us!
يخطّط للنيل منّا
Do you really think there's such a person in the forest?
أتظنّون أنّ شخصاً مثله في الغابة حقاً؟
Think back to the state of Ran's room when she was attacked...
أعيدوا التفكير بحالة غرفة ران عندما تعرّضت للهجوم
He broke in through the veranda, right?
دخل من الشرفة، صحيح؟
Yeah. He jumped onto the upstairs veranda from a tree.
أجل، صعد لشرفة الطابق الثاني عبر الشجرة
Then why were there no mud tracks in Ran's room?
لمَ لم تكن هناك آثار وحل في غرفة ران؟
It was raining outside when the bandaged man snuck in.
كان المطر يهطل عندما تسلّل رجل الضماد
Now that you mention it!
!صـ-صحيح
The reason is simple.
السبب بسيط
It was because the bandaged man was inside the lodge!
لأنّ رجل الضماد كان داخل السكن
The point of entry was most likely Chikako-san's room, right next to Ran's.
نقطة الدخول كانت غرفة تشيكاكو-سان بجوار غرفة ران على الأرجح
The killer exited onto the veranda, entered Ran's room, and attacked her.
خرج القاتل للشرفة منها ودخل غرفة ران ثمّ هاجمها
But then she screamed...
...لكنّ ران صرخت
...and he hastily ran back to Chikako-san's room!
فهرب بعجلة لغرفة تشيكاكو-سان
He quickly changed his clothes
وغيّر ثيابه هناك بمنتهى السرعة
and met everyone in Ran's room with feigned unawareness.
والتمّ بالجميع في غرفة ران بقناع الجهل على وجهه
In other words, the maniac who killed Chikako-san and attacked Ran
أي أنّ القاتل المجنون الذي قتل تشيكاكو-سان وهاجم ران
is in this very room!
!هو بيننا
Sonoko-chan. Playing detective is nice and all,
سونوكو-تشان، لا بأس من لعب لعبة المتحرّي
but think clearly.
لكن أمعني التفكير
When the bandaged dude ran past the window,
،عندما مرّ رجل الضماد بالنافذة
every one of us was inside the lodge!
كنّا جميعاً داخل السكن
None of us could possibly be him!
يستحيل أن يكون أحدنا
But if you used a dummy and some piano wire,
،لكن لو استعمل دميةً وأسلاك بيانو
it'd be possible to make it seem that way from inside!
يمكنه خداع أنظارنا من الداخل
A dummy?
د-دمية؟
Yes. An inflatable one, most likely.
أجل، دمية قابلة للنفخ على الأرجح
He affixed Chikako-san's body to the dummy,
،ثبّت جثّة تشيكاكو-سان بالدمية
and attached two piano wires to the dummy's head.
وربط سلكي بيانو برأس الدمية
He passed one wire through the central veranda's railing,
مرّر أحد السلكين بحاجز الشرفة الوسطى
tied both ends of the wires to the railing above the window in question,
وربط طرفَي السلكين بالحاجز فوق النافذة
and then cut the wire that went through the railing.
ثمّ قطع السلك الذي كان مربوطاً بالحاجز
After he swung it past the window,
،وبعدما لوّح بهما أمام النافذة
he quickly recovered the dummy and Chikako-san!
استرجع الدمية وتشيكاكو-سان سريعاً
Chikako!
!تشيكاكو
The only one who could've pulled that off
الوحيد القادر على ذلك
was the person on the veranda, fixing the roof...
كان الشخص على الشرفة الذي يصلح السقف وقتها
...you, Takahashi-san!
!تاكاهاشي-سان! لا أحد غيرك
You're kidding, right, Sonoko-chan?
أنتِ تمزحين يا سونوكو-تشان
The two distinct piano wire marks on the outside railing...
...آثار سلكَي البيانو الواضحة على حاجز الشرفة
...are proof!
!هي الدليل
Only the stage manager for your old filmmaking club
وحده مدير مسرح نادي إنتاج الأفلام
could've set up something so elaborate!
بإمكانه تجهيز شيء بهذه التفاصيل
You can't be serious...
...عـ-على مهلك
Then what did I do with the body after I pulled it up?
ماذا فعلتُ بالجثّة بعدما سحبتها إذاً؟
Right after that, we all chased him into the forest,
بعد ذلك مباشرة، لحقنا به جميعاً إلى الغابة
where we found Chikako's body in pieces.
حيث وجدنا أجزاء جثّة تشيكاكو
Did you see me carrying any bodies?
لم تروني أحمل جثّة وقتها، صحيح؟
No...
أجل
There is proof that you carried her.
هناك دليل لحملك لها
My sister found Chikako-san's choker by the door.
فقد وجدت أختي شريط عنق تشيكاكو-سان عند المدخل
She was wearing that choker when she was abducted.
كانت ترتدي الشريط عندما اُختُطِفت
The fact that it was by the front door after everyone left
وجوده عند المدخل بعد مغادرة الجميع
means that someone went through the door, carrying her body!
دليلٌ على أنّ أحدهم عبر الباب وهو يحمل جثّتها
I already told you, I wasn't carrying anything!
!أخبرتك، لم أكن أحمل شيئاً
Besides, nobody could carry the body without being noticed...
كما، كيف يمكن لأحد حمل جثّة دون أن يلاحظه أحد؟
Assuming it was the body.
بافتراض أنّها جثّة كاملة
But if it were just the head...
...لكن لو كان الرأس فقط
...it would be entirely possible to carry!
!فيمكن حمله
Eh?!
!ماذا؟
After all, all that we saw outside the window
فما رأيناه من النافذة
was her head surrounded by a cape!
!كان رأسها والمعطف يغطيها
Her body had been torn apart when we found it...
كانت جثّتها متراميةً عندما وجدناها
This is ridiculous!
!سخافة
Why would I want to kill her and Ran-chan?!
!لمَ قد أقتل تشيكاكو؟! كما أهاجم ران-تشان؟
And besides--
...أ-أيضاً... أيضاً
And besides what?
أيضاً؟
Why won't you say it?
لمَ لا تقولها؟
Isn't there proof?
أليس هناك دليل؟
You and the bandaged man have completely different figures...
تمتلك ورجل الضماد بُنيتين مختلفتين تماماً
That's right, Takahashi-kun!
!صحيح يا تاكاهاشي-كن
The bandaged man isn't fat!
!رجل الضماد ليس بديناً
Takahashi! Why didn't you say so?
تاكاهاشي، لمَ لم تقل ذلك؟
He was afraid of what I would ask in response:
كان يخشى ما سأسأله ردّاً على كلامه
"Are you really, truly fat?"
"أأنت بدينٌ حقاً؟"
That's right. He's not fat at all!
صحيح، ليس بديناً البتّة
He stuffed the head in his shirt and carried it out!
...لذا كان بإمكانه وضع الرأس داخل قميصه وحمله
First, he lured Chikako-san into the forest, ripped her apart,
استدرج تشيكاكو-سان للغابة أوّلاً وقطّع جسدها
replaced the padding under his shirt with her head,
واستبدل البطانة تحت قميصه برأسها
and carried it back to the lodge.
وأخذها للسكن
Then, after doing the trick on the veranda,
بعدها، بعد تنفيذ حيلة الشرفة
he stuffed the deflated dummy and head under his shirt
أعاد الدمية مفرغة الهواء والرأس تحت قميصه
and headed for the forest with everyone else.
وتوجّه للغابة مع الجميع
Then he dumped the head in the forest
ثمّ رمى رأسها في الغابة
while pretending to look for her.
مُتظاهراً بالبحث عنها
In other words, this was a daring and clever trick
أي أنّه زيّف بُنيته ليخدع الجميع
in which he faked his figure to freely move the corpse around!
!وينقل الجثّة بحريّة في حيلة بمُنتهى الجرأة والمكر
By using this trick, he was able to make it look like
باستعمال هذه الحيلة، تمكن من جعلنا نعتقد
the bandaged man took Chikako-san into the forest and killed her,
أنّ رجل الضماد أخذ تشيكاكو-سان للغابة وقتلها
and that he was responsible for everything that happened!
!وأنّه المسؤول عن كلّ ما حصل
But his supposedly-perfect plan
لكن خطّته المُتقنة ظاهرياً
began to mess up when Ran did something...
تفكّكت عندما فعلَتْ ران شيئاً
Yes. When she accidentally opened his door,
أجل، عندما فتحت باب غرفته عن طريق الخطأ
she saw it...
رأت
...his real figure!
!بُنيته الحقيقية
She hadn't thought much of it at the time,
لم تهتم ران بالأمر وقتها
but if she did remember, his carefully-planned murder plot
لكن إذا تذكّرَتْ، فخطّة قتله المدروسة
would go up in smoke!
!ستتبخّر
That's why he attacked her in the forest--
لذا هاجمها في الغابة
to keep her quiet!
!لإسكاتها
But he failed.
لكنّه فشل
Worried that Chikako-san would go down the mountain
وفي قلقه من أن تغادر تشيكاكو-سان التي كانت هدفه الرئيسي
during all the commotion,
،أثناء كلّ هذه الفوضى
he cut the phone line, destroyed the bridge,
قطع خطّ الهاتف وأسقط الجسر
and shut everyone up inside the lodge!
واحتجز الجميع في السكن
He lured Chikako-san into the forest as planned
استدرج تشيكاكو-سان للغابة كما خطّط
and then murdered her.
وقتلها
She was lured out by the note
استدرجها برسالة
that he most likely slipped under her door.
وضعها تحت بابها على الأرجح
It was probably about fellow club member Atsuko-san,
كان موضوعها غالباً أتسوكو-سان زميلة أختي في النادي
who committed suicide two years ago--
التي انتحرت قبل عامين
It's true! I did it all for Atsuko!
!صحيح! فعلتُ كلّ هذا لأجل أتسوكو
T-Takahashi...
...تـ-تاكاهاشي
She secretly showed me a story she had written,
أطلعتني سرّاً على قصّةٍ كتبتها
and her eyes sparkled as she told me her dream of being a novelist.
ولمعت عيناها بينما تكلمت عن حلمها في أن تصبح روائية
Then, one day, she hanged herself in our meeting room!
لكن، شنقت نفسها فجأةً في غرفة اجتماعنا
Once I saw Chikako's latest movie, "Blue Kingdom,"
"عندما رأيتُ فيلم تشيكاكو الأخير، "المملكة الزرقاء
I suddenly knew why she did it!
!أدركتُ السبب بوضوح
"Blue Kingdom"?\
المملكة الزرقاء؟
Don't tell me she-
...أ-أيمكن
That's right. The story for Chikako's debut work
أجل، قصّة عمل تشيكاكو الرسميّ الأوّل
was exactly the same as the "Azure Country" story that Atsuko showed me!
!كانت مُطابقة لـ "البلد الأزرق" الذي أرتني إيّاه أتسوكو
You mean Chikako...
...أتقصد أنّ تشيكاكو
...stole it?!
سرقته؟
Yeah. The story won Chikako a new scriptwriter's award
أجل، فازت تشيكاكو بجائزة كاتب السيناريو الواعد بفضله
while she was still in school, and now she's famous!
بينما كانت لا تزال تدرس، وأصبحت شهيرةً الآن
But how do we know that led to Atsuko's suicide?
لكن كيف تجزم بأنّه سبب انتحار أتسوكو؟
The day Chikako won the award-- the day before Atsuko died--
يوم فوز تشيكاكو بالجائزة، أي اليوم السابق لموت أتسوكو
Atsuko told me over the phone
أخبرتني أتسوكو على الهاتف
that she couldn't trust anyone anymore!
!أنّها لم تعد تستطيع الثقة بأحد
So I lured Chikako into the forest with a blackmail note
لذا استدرجتُ تشيكاكو للغابة برسالة "تهديد لفضح سرقة "البلد الأزرق
and then I chopped her head off!
!وقطعتُ رأسها
That's what she gets for crushing Atsuko's dream!
!هذا ما تستحقه لقطع حُلم أتسوكو
It's all over now...
...انتهى
It's time for me to see Atsuko...
حان وقت ذهابي لأتسوكو
Hold on, Takahashi!
!ا-انتظر يا تاكاهشي
Stay away!
!ابتعدوا
Takahashi-kun!
!تاكاهاشي-كن
I'm going to live with her in the next world
سأذهب للعيش معها في العالم الآخر
as the messenger of justice who avenged her!
!بصفتي رسول العدالة الذي أخذ بثأرها
Stop fooling yourself!
!يكفي هراءً
If you wanna die, then die!
!إذا أردت الموت فلتمت يا وغد
Sonoko...
...سـ-سونوكو
Maybe you did commit a crime for Atsuko's sake.
ربما أقدمت على خطيئة لأجل أتسوكو-سان
But when you attacked Ran,
،لكن عندما هاجمت ران
it wasn't for her sake at all!
لم يكن لأجلها أبداً
You were afraid!
كنت خائفاً
You were afraid of being labeled a criminal, so you attacked her!
!خائفاً من أن تُضبط كمجرم فهاجمتها
You're no...
...أنتَ لست
...messenger of justice!
رسول عدالة
You're just an ugly, bloodthirsty killer!
!مجرّد قاتل بشع متعطّش للدماء
A friend's betrayal led to a friend's death,
قادت خيانة صديق لموت آخر
which, in turn, twisted a friend's heart...
مما أدّى لسواد قلب صديقٍ
At long last, the villa breaks free of the cold and tragic night...
انقشع ظلام المأساة البارد عن السكن أخيراً
But beware!
لكن احذروا
Let your guard down, and he'll appear
افتحوا له طريقاً وسيعاود الظهور
from a person's heart again...
داخل قلب إنسان
The crazed killer known as "revenge."
القاتل المجنون المعروف بالانتقام
I'm glad your sister is doing better now!
أنا مسرورة لكون أختك في حالٍ أفضل الآن
Yeah, me too.
أنا أيضاً
She stayed in bed for a whole week after it happened...
فقد لازمت الفراش لأسبوع بعد الحادثة
But it was all thanks to your great detective skills
لكن حُلّت القضية
that the case was solved!
!بفضل استنتاجاتك البارعة
Eh?
ماذا؟
Uh oh!
!كـ-كلا
You make a pretty cool detective, you know that?
!بدوتِ متحرّيةً رائعة
I better change the topic!
!عليّ تغيير الموضوع
Hey, guess what--
...بالمناسبة
Yeah, well, cases like that are as easy as pie for me.
أجل، فقضايا كتلك كشرب الماء بالنسبة لي
Shinichi-kun and your dad are out of luck...
زمن شينتشي-كن ووالدك قد ولّى
It's the great detective Suzuki Sonoko's time now!
!إنّه عصر المتحرية العظيمة سوزوكي سونوكو الآن
Having her be the detective was definitely a big mistake...
جعلها متحرية كان غلطةً كبيرة بالفعل
Dr. Yoko has a motive for killing Nakamoto-san.
تملك الطبيبة يوكو دافعاً لقتل ناكاموتو-سان
But she has an airtight alibi!
لكن لديها حجّة غياب قويّة
If she was the killer, then--
...إذا كانت القاتلة
There's no VCR here...
لا يوجد مشغّل فيديو هنا
Aha! So that's how!
!هكذا إذاً! فهمت
This was an alibi trick involving Ayumi-chan!
كانت هذه حيلة حجّة غياب !باستعمال أيومي-تشان
On the next Conan--
في الحلقة القادمة من كونان
"The Monday, 7:30 P.M. Murder Case."
جريمة قتل يوم الإثنين، 7:30 مساءً
Next Conan's Hint:
تلميح الحلقة القادمة
Curtains.
ستائر